# Jim Silvester

Software Developer | Specialising in Front-End Web, Mobile Apps, and Video Games

Merrickville, ON, Canada | (613) 912-9896 jim@extralargebacon.pizza | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Leetcode</u>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled Programmer, Developer, and Designer with over 10 years of experience. Specialising in Front-End Web, Mobile App, and Video Game development. Named inventor on a patent. Developed mobile apps with user's bases exceeding 100,000. Well versed in all aspects of software development including: Planning, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Testing, and Maintenance. Experienced in designing User Interfaces, Novel Human Computer Interactions, and Video Games using an Agile Scrum Methodology.

#### **LANGUAGES**

C, C#, C++, CSS, HTML5, Java, JavaScript, Lua, MySQL, PHP, Python, SCSS, Swift, TypeScript

#### **TOOLS**

Android Studio, Angular, Arduino, Bootstrap, Git, Unity 3D, Visual Studio Code, Xamarin, Xcode

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Independent Contractor, Extra Large Bacon Pizza, 2020 - Current

- Engineered and deployed websites for clients, showcasing code mastery in HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Led the entire process from conception to execution, utilising Visual Studio Code for efficient development and Git for collaborative version control.
- Meticulously designed and implemented a 2000 watt volcanic eruption LED mobile art installation for a Burning Man Art Car. Managed the complete engineering build ensuring full reliability of installation for harsh weather conditions and usage.
- Built multiple mobile apps and chrome extensions for the purpose of blocking ads on YouTube and Reddit.

#### Intermediate Software Engineer, ASAP (Formerly BiteSquad), 2018 - 2020

- Integral part of a three-member front-end mobile app team, overseeing the entire engineering build, implementation, and debugging process of Android and iOS consumer apps. Employed Xamarin.Android and Xamarin.iOS, managing codebase through Visual Studio Code, Jira, Bugsee, and Git.
- Personally spearheaded screens implementation, ensuring pixel-perfect UI designs and seamless user interactions throughout the entire app..
- Monthly user bases exceeding 100,000, helping the company to expand the app's reach to over 50 cities in the USA.
- Implemented rigorous testing methodologies, resulting in a remarkable app crash rate of less than 0.1%.
- Thrived as a member of a cross functional team, actively participating in collaborative efforts of design and testing, contributing insights, and fostering innovation within the development process.

# Jim Silvester

Software Developer | Specialising in Front-End Web, Mobile Apps, and Video Games

# Lead UI/UX Developer and Designer, Biointeractive Technologies, 2016 - 2018

- Responsible for the software development supporting first of its kind wearable smart strap technology which detects hand gestures and finger motion. Used primarily for gesture control, stroke rehabilitation, and repetitive stress injury monitoring.
- Designed and developed all software used for technology demonstrations, sensor visualisation, device connections, progress tracking, IoT controller, virtual reality controller, video game controller, and other assorted demos using Unity3D and Android Studio.
- Filed a patent as the principal inventor for titled: "Apparatus And Methods For Detecting, Quantifying, and Providing Feedback On User Gestures" (Serial number 16/763,769).
- Collaborated seamlessly with the hardware production team, ensuring a harmonious integration of software and hardware elements for a comprehensive user experience.

#### Lead Research and Teaching Assistant, Simon Fraser University, 2012 - 2016

- Developed several multiplayer video games used in experiments by a team of Ph.D Economists.
- Lead and mentored over 90 students in weekly immersive programming and design workshops, emphasising hands-on screen implementation and debugging techniques throughout the entire process.
- Teaching Assistant for the following courses: 4th year Advanced Game Design (three times), 2nd year Multimedia Programming for Art & Design (twice), and 2nd year Human Computer Interaction.

## Director of Technical Development, Global Advantage Consulting, 2010 - 2012

- Developed data visualisation tools that use dynamic data sets to help analyse global innovation systems.
- Designed and built several websites including the company's website, content management systems, and database driven websites.

### **EDUCATION**

Simon Fraser University, School of Interactive Arts and Technology 2012 - 2014 Graduate Studies Coursework

Carleton University, School of Information Technology 2008 - 2012
Bachelor of Information Technology – Interactive Multimedia and Design

**Algonquin College, School of Media and Design** 2008 - 2012 Advanced Technology Diploma – Interactive Multimedia and Design